CHANDRAVEER SINGH

New Delhi, India 110046 | +91-9717581194 | cvsingh.acct@gmail.com

Professional Summary

A pro-active, self-motivated and results oriented team player more than 15 years of experience in various aspects of corporate accounting & finance such as investments analysis & ROI preparation, budget forecast & cash flow management, financial management and operation management. Gifted in building and leading solid teams to handle high-volume operations with consistency, accuracy and full compliance with regulatory requirements.

Skills

- Financial Management
- Corporate Accounting
- Operations Management
- Strategic and Financial Planning
- Budget Forecast
- Stock Management
- Taxation
- Impot/Export Operations

Work History

HOD (Accounts & Finance)

04/2020 to Current

Nexime Technologies Indust e Servicos Lda – Angola

- Maintains accounting & administrative controls by preparing and recommending policies and procedures.
- Reviewed and analyzed financial accounting information and presented analysis and commentary to key business partners.
- Worked to ensure that the financial control framework in place to ensure the accurate reporting of financial conditions.
- Provide financial reports and interpret financial information to management while recommending further courses of action.
- Generating monthly MIS reports including updated cash flow & ROI variance analysis report for H.O and shareholders.
- Lease with auditors to ensure appropriate monitoring of company finances is maintained.
- Indirect and Direct Taxes, Sale Tax, Service Tax, Income tax of the company including filling the returns.
- Conducting periodical stock verifications & maintaining daily stock records.
- Investigated intercompany books variances and corrected errors to resolve discrepancies.
- Communicate with suppliers, shipping line and clearing agents for smooth import process.

Senior Finance Manager

Angochrist Comercio Geral Lda – Angola

01/2017 to 03/2020

- Manage a team to maintain company book of accounts according to accounting standard.
- Prepare budget forecasts based on project requirement.
- Prepare and publish monthly, quarterly and annual financial reports.
- Control & analise accounts payable ageing on monthly basis.
- Manage project wise balance sheets and profit/loss statements draft.
- Report on the project's financial health and liquidity.
- Audit financial and accounting transactions with real-time documents
- Evaluate and apply internal controls to achieve accurate and efficient accounting systems and compliance with company, professional, and government accounting practices.
- Developing and implementing accounting policies and procedures.
- Balance Sheet framing with completes Balance Sheet & Profit & Loss details
- Administering the entire books of accounts, Full banking operation, Cash & Inventory management.
- Analise stock movement, re-ordering status, Purchase order, Job order.
- Generating weekly & monthly MIS reports for submitting to H.O
- Supervise controls for accounting procedures and systems, monthly provisions.
- Company financial reporting including the preparation of regular financial statements, necessary corporate filings, and specialized management reports

Accounts & Finance Manager

01/2015 to 12/2016

Ocean Star Electronics, Tristar Group – Angola

- Administering the entire operation along with the finance and accounts activities in the organization
- Analyzed financial discrepancies and provided solutions for accurate financial records.
- Assisted management with annual expense plans to strategically track income or revenue.
- Completed financial reports, providing insight into performance, operations and cash flow.
- Oversaw and managed cost accounting, capitalizing variances, and inventory provisions.
- Properly reviewed and supported the preparation of entries related to business operations.
- Completed the documentation of processes and standardized operating procedures.
- Prepared monthly, quarterly, and annual reports for corporate reporting.
- Indirect and Direct Taxes of the company, up to filling the return and monthly payable taxes.
- Communicated and resolved disputes with clients regarding outstanding invoices, payments and adjustments.

Accounts Manager

10/2010 to 12/2014

XL Media Lda – Angola

- Administering the entire books of accounts, Banking operation, Cash & Inventory management activities in the organization.
- Controlling Sales invoicing, Purchase, Accounts Payable, Accounts Receivable,
- Generated financial and operational reports to assist management with business strategy.
- Developing and implementing accounting policies and procedures

- Indirect and Direct Taxes of the company, up to filling the return and monthly payable taxes
- Procurement management, Support and supervise service provider procurement and contracting
- Balance Sheet framing with completes Balance Sheet & Profit & Loss details.
- Analyzing stock movement, re-ordering status, Purchase order, Job order

Associate Accounts Manager

03/2009 to 10/2010

Solutions Integrated Marketing Services Pvte Ltd – Delhi -India

- Maintaining book of accounts of the company such as all financial records, Generate P.O,
 Invoicing etc
- Analyze every voucher entered in system by other team member before approving
- Handling Indirect and Direct taxes such as service tax, VAT and TDS up to filling the return
- Payable / Receivable & Bank/cash handling up to reconciliation of accounts
- Deal with the clients to reconcile book of accounts statement
- Regular follow-up with customers for bill collection
- Balance Sheet framing with completes Balance Sheet & Profit & Loss details

Sr. Accounts Executive 11/2006 to 03/2009

Arms Communications Pvt. Ltd - Delhi-India

- Generate Sales invoice & maintain records (Purchase, Payable, Receivable, Banking operation, Cash management etc.)
- Data entry of day-to-day basis and prepare necessary records
- Attending statutory & internal auditors in their Audit work
- Indirect & direct tax monthly deposit and filling of Annual Return
- Submission of an overall cash movement report & collection report over a month program
- Handle financial issues with the client (timely estimation, billing and collection)

Education

Master of Business Administration (MBA): Finance & Marketing

12/2010

Amity University - Noida, U.P

Master of Commerce: Accounting and Finance 06/2006

Mahatma Jyotiba Phule Rohilkhand University - Bareilly, U.P

Bachelor of Commerce: Corporate Accounting & Financial Management 06/2004 **Mahatma Jyotiba Phule Rohilkhand University** - Bareilly-U.P

Corporate Accounting, Financial Accounting, Financial Management, Auditing & Taxation

Diploma: Corporate Accounting & Finance

03/2008

Institute of Professional Accounting - Delhi

Languages

English Portuguese Spanish